

# DIBYENDU KANKALIA

4872 Martingale Drive Woodbury, MN 55129

Email: dibyendu.kankalia@gmail.com

Cell Phone: 410-967-0587

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

16+ years experience in Architecting and developing Web, Windows, and distributed applications. 7+ years experience in manufacturing domain.

**Certified AWS Solution Architect and Developer** for Manufacturing Product Group developing strategy, design, and implementation of custom manufacturing execution systems (MES) and solutions focused on shop floor production planning and execution.

## **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

AWS	Certified AWS Solutions Architect - Associate, AWS Developer - Associate and AWS			
11110	SysOps. Administrator – Associate			
	IAM, S3, EC2, EBS, EFS, Lambda, CloudFront, CloudWatch, RDS, DynamoDB, Route53, ELB,			
	AMI, VPC, NAT Instance, NAT Gateway, SQS, SNS, API Gateway, Cloud Formation, ECS,			
	Fargate, CodeCommit, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, Code Pipeline. Kinesis, AWS IOT			
Web Frameworks,	ASP.NET MVC, ASP.Net Core, Entity Framework, C#, VB, ASP, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, JQuery,			
Languages and	Bootstrap, Require JS, Mediatr, Serilog			
Tools	ReactJS, Redux, React Router, Angular, Knockout, Nodejs, Express, Apache Kafka,			
	NserviceBus, Ansible, Powershell, Less, Sass, Gulp, Bower, NPM, Nuget			
	Docker Containers, Docker compose, Microservices, IIS, Apache, Kestrel			
Windows	Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF), Windows Workflow Foundation (WF)			
Services	WCF, Web API, SOAP, REST Based Http Services, NServiceBus, Windows Services			
Databases	SQL Server 2016, Oracle 9i/10G, MongoDB, Redis, RDS, Aurora, DynamoDB			
Data Visualization	Dynatrace, Splunk, Elastic Search. Serilog			
Software CI/CD	GitHub/Bitbucket/Stash, Jira, TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, Ansible, Powershell tools, VSS,			
Automation Tools	Spectrum SCM, VSTS, CodeCommit, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, CodePipeline			
Workflow	Savigent Certified Workflow Developer & Savigent Certified Engine Developer -			
	Savigent Workflow, Model, Engine Design and Deployment Plugins, Server Installation and			
	Setup (System Design and Management), Custom Agents			
MES/ERP	3M MES, SAP ECC, SAP EWM, IMES			
Identity Servers &	ADFS2, Thinktecture Identity Server, Aws Cognito, Okta, OAuth, Open id Connect, WS-			
Authentication	Federation based passive/active Authentication and Authorization, Security Token Service			
	JWT, SAML, X509 Certificates			
Systems & Tools	Wonderware (Application Server, InTouch, Historian, DASS, OPC Server), IBM Maximo			
	Asset Management, Savigent, SAP PP, SAP MII Services, NServiceBus, ADFS, F5 Load			
	Balancer, Visual Studio 2019, Visual Studio Code, Balsamiq			
Test Tools	NUnit, Fixie, SOAP UI, Postman			

- Excellent technical skills in Windows and Web technologies using .NET, C# and SQL Server
- ♣ Excellent problem solving, analytical, interpersonal skills and possess good work ethics
- Strong team player having excellent communication and leadership abilities.
- Excellent learning capability and technology enthusiast.
- Expert in single sign on authentication implementation of Passive and Active Federation using ADFS
- Experience in procurement of Servers, setup, automated deployment, development & support.
- Expertise in dev ops with continuous build, integration & deployment using Bitbucket, Teamcity, Octopus
- ♣ Good knowledge using tools like Dynatrace, Splunk and Elastic Search
- Excellent knowledge in OOPS, SOLID principles, Database design and design patterns
- Excellent knowledge in integration with SAP ECC and EWM
- ♣ Personal Development Repository <a href="https://github.com/dibyenduk">https://github.com/dibyenduk</a>

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## 3M MES (MANUFACTURING EXECUTION SYSTEM)

CLIENT - 3M COMPANY, ST. PAUL, MN (JUN 2014 - CURRENT)

SOLUTION ARCHITECT / TECHNICAL ANALYST AND LEAD

- Cognizant Solution Architect / 3M Technical Analyst and Lead for developing custom web-based manufacturing execution system solution / product integrating with SAP ECC and EWM enabling global business transformation at 3M.
- Focus on architecting UI / REST API solution design, development, security (ADFS), continuous integration & continuous deployment, automated unit test, integration, code review & infrastructure preparation.
- Delivering operational intelligence to ensure visibility to issues impacting availability, response time, application performance ensuring product scalability of 3M MES as a product.
- Utilizing Savigent platform to enable user guided workflow and connect 3M MES to the shop floor PLCs and devices for data collection and execution.
- Project Manager and Technical Lead for multiple Savigent based workflow applications reading data from shop floor and sending it to MES / SAP.

# STRATEGIC ASSET MANAGEMENT SOLUTION (SAMS)

CLIENT - 3M COMPANY, ST. PAUL, MN (JUL 2013 - JUN 2014)

ASSET MANAGEMENT CONSULTANT

- Maximo Technical Specialist and Onsite coordinator for SAMS / CMMS enterprise asset management COTS product by IBM
- Focus on leading onsite project delivery with customization and delivery of Maximo customization features
- Activities included working with Plant Engineering Services to understand requirements, analyze business rules in Maximo, design, layout plan for implementation, code review, test and deploy in production

#### **ESCAPE SUPERVISION AND CONTROL SYSTEM**

CLIENT - IKUSI, SPAIN (FEB 2010 - JUN 2013)

TECHNICAL LEAD

- Technical Lead for development of security and traffic management product for IKUSI.
- Product allowed user to monitor and control all systems related to traffic and security from main control center. Integration of product with subsystems and devices provided by third party vendors.
- Focused on development of next gen rich Graphical user interface for configuration and visualization of maps and devices allowing user to zoom, pan and select elements for navigation.
- Integration with Invensys Wonderware product and devices / subsystems like Interphone, Entrance, PA Zone, Megaphone, PMV, CCTV System.

#### RESOURCE SCHEDULER

CLIENT - CANRIG DRILLING TECHNOLOGY LTD, HOUSTON, TX (MAR 2007 - JAN 2010) LEAD DEVELOPER

- Lead Developer for migrating existing VB 6.0 application to VB.NET
- Worked on enhancements for the RS.NET 4.0 application.
- Worked on creation extensions and plugins to integrate RS.NET with external third party applications like Aries.
- Provided support for RS 3.6 and RS.NET 4.0 applications.

#### HUMMINGBIRD

CLIENT - LUTRON ELECTRONICS COMPANY INC., PHILADELPHIA, PA (SEP 2006 - MAR 2007)
DEVELOPER / IT ANALYST

• Developer for building management product for Lutron providing centralized control for lights and shades in the building from a single control center. Application included controlling light ballast and shades using opcodes based on time of the day and alarms created in the application.



#### **ELECTRONIC LOG**

CLIENT - VIACOM INC., NEW YORK, NY (OCT 2005 – FEB 2006) LEAD DEVELOPER / IT ANALYST

- Lead Developer for creation of electronic log application used for maintaining information related to airing of programs, program schedules, programs that aired and which did not, if a program did not air, the reason it was not aired, and discrepancies or problems that occurred while airing those programs.
- Involved in requirement analysis, design, functionality and screen design, coding, writing unit test cases, testing, reviewing code and fixing defects.

#### **OAP.NET**

CLIENT - VIACOM INC., NEW YORK, NY (JUL 2005 – SEP 2005) DEVELOPER

• Programmer for On Air Promotion tracking web application for VIACOM networks.

## **IBM MAINFRAME TO.NET MIGRATION**

CLIENT - SIMON AND SCHUSTER INC., NEW JERSEY (AUG 2004 - JUN 2005) PROGRAMMER ANALYST

- Programmer for migrating the existing IBM Mainframe system to ASP.NET Web application.
- Cobol, JCL Development

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Feb 2010 - Present	Cognizant Technology Solutions U.S Corp	Sr. Manager
Oct 2004 - Feb 2010	Tata Consultancy Services	I.T Analyst

#### **EDUCATION**

Executive Certificate in Management Program	McIntire School of Commerce,	May 2017	Distinction
	University of Virginia, USA		
Bachelor of Engineering (Computer)	University of Pune, India	May 2004	First Class

#### CERTIFICATES

Certificate Name	Certificate Provider	Validation Number
AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (SAA)	Amazon Web Services	JV3YGGG2FMQ115S6
AWS Certified Developer - Associate (DVA)	Amazon Web Services	F6NTDBJ2KB11Q2GB
AWS Certified SysOps. Administrator - Associate	Amazon Web Services	35687NTLKJVQQ93X
Savigent Certified Model & Workflow Developer	Savigent Software	NA
Savigent Certified Engine Developer	Savigent Software	NA